

+44 7831026965







andrea.castegnaro@outlook.com

Portfolio: https://lenakeiz.github.io/index.html

Interdisciplinary researcher with a can-do attitude. PhD in Cognitive Neuroscience with a background in physics and game development. Interested in bridging the gap between healthcare/education and digital technology for specific category of people. Experience with data analysis, statistical interference and data modelling. Highly adaptable and able to operate effectively within fast-changing environments proven by work experience in diverse fields and different countries.

Education	
PhD in Cognitive Neuroscience, UCL UK MSc (Distinction) in Computer Games and Entertainment, Goldsmiths University UK BSc, MSc (Distinction) Physics, University of Rome II Italy	2015/2020 2014/2015 2006/2012

Experience

Lead Unity Developer, part-time

2017 – ongoing

SoftV | London, UK

- Developed the <u>Listen-In</u> and <u>Swan</u> games for treatment of aphasia in adults and developmental difficulties in children. Listen-In, released April 2021, delivers 100 hours of therapy and over 30 hours of game content. The game has been already listed in research publications reporting an increase of ~30% in listening accuracy in patients after a stroke
- Designed and implemented the frontend part of the game (gameplay, UI) through iterations with feedbacks from focus groups to target specific user experience (Listen-In)
- 2D Physics based gameplay for the game content (Listen-In)
- Contributed to the design and implementation of the backend for the data collection using PhP and MySQL (Listen-In)
- Lead a small team of artists, game designers, developers to deliver releases and manage different iterations of the game (Listen-In)
- Improved gameplay experience with data collection for assessing improvements through the app by adding two mini-games (Swan). Swan is going into clinical trial in April 2021.
- Implemented data collection and storage using PhP API (Swan)

Postdoc Researcher (Cognitive Neuroscience)

Jan 2021 – ongoing

University College London | London, UK

- Developing a mathematical model for distinguishing different contributions to navigation errors made by people at risk of Alzheimer. The model is being developed in Matlab using the stats and global optimization toolboxes
- Developing a CAVE VR system to perform electrophysiology experiments on mice while performing
 navigation tasks. Includes an interface that will be used by the experimenter to control experiments
 in real-time. Portions include network (TCP/UDP) programming for client/server communication.
 Customization of Unity editor to enable experimenters to create and setup experiments with a
 minimum amount of code required

Experience (continuing)

PhD Researcher (Cognitive Neuroscience)

2016 - 2020

University College London | London, UK

- Conceived and managed self-led PhD research project within inter-disciplinary working group
- Designed and created different VR tasks using HTC Vive to assess cognitive decline in early onset Alzheimer's disease
- Developed a shader-based grass technique in HLSL necessary for one of the experiment manipulations
- Implemented local backend to let clinicians customize the task
- Data collection, cleansing, processing, and manipulation using Matlab, Python, R and SPSS
- Statistical modelling based on ANOVA, GLM (statistics and machine learning toolbox in Matlab)
- Published results in high impact scientific journals (<u>Google Scholar profile</u>) One study is currently in the top 5% of all research outputs from research articles of that journal with similar age

Junior .NET developer

01/2013 - 08/2014

Electric80 S.p.A | Reggio Emilia, Italy

- Using company proprietary software written in C# .NET I implemented algorithms to control dispatching orders to laser guided vehicle and a client user interface using WPF
- Using company proprietary software written in SQL I built the database to store information of the client products, create views with queries using Entity Framework and manage the automatic shipping using stored procedures

Skills and Interests

Legend: experienced (e), intermediate (i), basic (b)

Programming: C# (e), SQL (e), Matlab (e), C++ (i), Python (i), R (i), PhP (b), HLSL (b), Java (b)

Software: Unity (e), MATLAB (e), SPSS (i), Unreal (b), Maya (b)

Languages: English (e), Italian (mother tongue)

Interests: Charity runner with Goodgym. Bike tourist. Seasoned basketball player. Arduino lover.

Amateur cook.